一开始什么也没有…
诱惑导致罪恶
被逐出伊甸园的亚当和夏娃…
…有三个儿子
该隐，亚伯与塞特
该隐杀了亚伯，逃至东方
由一群堕落的天使庇护着他
“守望者”
这些守望者帮助该隐的子孙
建造出伟大的工业文明
这些城市所散播的邪恶…
…吞噬了整个世界
只有塞特的子孙…
…还传承着创世的纯真与良善
如今，他最新的血脉长大成人
亚当生了塞特，塞特生了以挪士
From Adam to Seth, from Seth to Enosh,
以挪士生了该南，该南生了玛勒列
Enosh to Kenan, Kenan to Mahalalel,
再来是我的父亲，玛土撒拉，接着是我
to my father, Methuselah, then to me.
今天开始由你来继承我们
Today, that birthright passes to you,
诺亚
Noah.
我的儿子
My son.
造物主按自己的形像创造了亚当
The Creator made Adam in His image,
让他治理整个世界
and then placed the world in his care.
现在开始就是你的责任了
This is your work now.  Your responsibility.
愿你心存公义，与造物主同行
May you walk  alongside The Creator in righteousness.
我告诉你…
So I say to you...
塞特的子嗣！
The Shrine of Seth!
有人来了
Men.
躲起来
Hide.
我们要在这里采矿
We mine here.
这块土地富含光石
The ground is rich with Tzohar.
这是造物主的土地，你在做什么？
This is The Creator's land.  What are you doing?
造物主？
The Creator?
我的矿坑都已枯竭
My mines run dry.
我的城市正在败坏，需要资源
My city withers and must be fed.
他做了什么？
And what has He done?
他诅咒我们必须汗流浃背  才得以苟且偷生！
He cursed us to struggle  by the sweat of our brow to survive!
所以我不择手段也要活下去
Damned if I don't do everything it takes  to do just that.
所以我要什么…
Damned if I don't take
…我就去拿
what I want.
这片土地现在属于该隐的子孙
This relic belongs to  the descendants of Cain now.
塞特的血脉到此为止
The line of Seth ends here.
是我们的了，开始挖！
It is ours. Now dig!
含
Ham.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
它好漂亮
It's pretty.
你看看其他花朵？
You see those other flowers?
它们是不是都生长在地上？
How they're attached to the ground?
它们就是该在那里的
That's where they should be.
这是有目的的
They have a purpose.
它们会发芽
They sprout.
会开花
And they bloom.
风带走种子，让花不断生长
The wind takes their seeds  and more flowers grow.
我们只采集可用和所需的量
We only collect what we can use  and what we need.
懂吗？
Do you understand?
闪
Shem.
含
Ham.
我们走
Let's go.
有人来了，躲起来
Men. Hide, hide.
快
Go.
你发现了我们的猎物
You found our kill.
真幸运
How fortunate.
但对你来说可能是不幸
But for you maybe not.
你知道我们有多久没吃肉吗？
You know how long it is  since we ate meat?
多久没看见动物了吗？
Since we even saw an animal?
别轻举妄动
Easy.
别这样，你想要什么？
Please. What do you want?
正义
Justice.
- 他们为什么要杀它？  - 吃它的肉
Why did they kill it?  They eat them.
为什么？
Why?
他们以为这样可以变强壮
They think it makes them stronger.
可以吗？
Is it true?
他们忘记了…
They forget
…真正的力量来自造物主
strength comes from The Creator.
妈妈！
Mama!
Mommy!
哥哥们回来了？
See your brothers?
含看见人狩猎了
Ham saw men hunting today.
他们离我们越来越近了
They are getting closer.
含有什么反应？
How was he?
他有点太好奇了
A little too interested.
他迟早都会见到
He had to see it sometime.
我还看见了其他东西
I saw something else.
一朵花…
A flower
…从无到有
bloom from nothing.
休息吧
Rest.
或许他将导正一切
Perhaps He will finally  make things right.
玛土撒拉
Methuselah.
他对你说话了吗？
Did He speak to you?
应该是
I think so.
他会帮助我们吗？
Will He help us?
他要毁灭世界
He's going to destroy the world.
这段旅程对孩子们来说又长又危险
It's a long and dangerous journey  for the boys.
你怎么知道你祖父还活着？
How do you know  your grandfather's still alive?
我不知道
I don't.
但我梦见了他住的山头
I saw his mountain.
他可能知道我们该怎么做
We need to go and find out  if he knows what we're to do.
闪，可以帮我的忙吗？
Shem. Can you help me with this?
我们可以带着孩子找个地方躲起来
We could take the boys  and find a place to hide.
我们无处可躲
There'll be no hiding.
我们早该出发了
We should have left already.
我来教你怎么做
Ham, let me show you how to do that.
放进这里面
Push it in here.
下次我们来的时候
Next time we come through,
这些东西就能派上用场
we'll know  we've got certain things we might need.
城市就在前面
There are cities ahead.
我们不会走太近
We will not get too close.
那是光石矿坑吗？
Is that a Tzohar mine?
曾经是，但矿藏已经耗尽
It was once. Before they dug it all up.
我们该绕过去吗？
Should we go around?
不必
No.
他们都死了吗？
Do you think they're all dead?
看起来是如此
It looks that way.
他们一定是在这里扎营
They must have been scavenging here.
然后再被别人打劫
And someone scavenged from them.
爸爸！
Dada!
跟紧我
Stay close.
爸爸！
Father!
这里！
Here!
让我看看？
May I see?
放轻松
Let me see.
你叫什么名字？
Tell me your name.
你有名字吗？
You have a name?
伊拉
Ila.
我叫伊拉
My name is Ila.
伊拉
Ila.
没事了
You're going to be all right, Ila.
他是闪
This is Shem.
他会紧握你的手  不会放开
He's going to hold your hand tight  and he won't let go.
到山顶！快！快！
Up the hill! Hurry! Hurry!
我们得走了，动作快
We have to go. Now.
往上爬，快跑
Up the hill. Run.
我们不能去那里
We can't go there.
我们别无选择，快！
We have no choice. Hurry!
别过去！  那里有巨人！
Hold, men! Hold!  The giants!
他们会杀了你们！
They'll kill you!
闪！
Shem!
无论如何一定要保护妈妈
Protect your mother, first and last.
我爱你
I love you.
快跑！
Run!
诺亚
Noah.
诺亚，你没事吧？
Noah. Are you all right?
我们是来见我的祖父玛土撒拉的
We are to see Methuselah.  My grandfather.
长者的子孙？
A child of the old one?
你应该杀死它们的
You should have killed them.
可是，撒米亚扎…
But, Samyaza...
这可是人啊，@
This is a man, Og.
你忘了他们是怎么背叛造物主的吗？
Do you forget how  they betrayed The Creator?
是他要我们来的！
It is He who sends us!
它说谎！
It lies!
让它们在这里自生自灭
Leave them here to rot.
他们是什么？
What are they?
守望者
The Watchers.
爸爸？
Dada?
睡吧
Sleep now.
唱歌给我听
Sing to me.
我想要我爸爸唱歌给我听
I want my daddy to sing to me.
我跟你一样很小的时候就失去了父亲
You know, I, too,  lost my father when I was very young.
每次我睡不着他都会唱一首歌
There's a song  he used to sing me sometimes  when I couldn't sleep.
你想听吗？
Would you like to hear it?
月亮高挂
The moon is high
枝条缠绕
The trees entwine
你的父亲等待着…
Your Father waits for thee
…将你抱入怀中
To wrap you in His sheltering wings
轻声哄你入睡
And whisper you to sleep
你的父亲是…
Your Father is
…那疗愈的风
The healing wind
轻声哄你入睡
That whispers you to sleep
That whispers as you sleep
她的伤口很深
It's an ugly wound.
这辈子都无法生儿育女了
She'll never have children.
但如果她能熬过这场高烧
If the fever doesn't take her,
就能活下来
I think she'll live.
跟我来
Follow me.
抱歉让你们受惊了
I'm sorry I frightened you.
守望者很清楚人类的可怕
Watchers have learned to fear men.
那你为什么要帮助我们？
Then why are you helping us?
造物主在第二天创造了我们
The Creator formed us  on the second day.
同一天他也创造了天
The day He made the heavens.
我们看守亚当和夏娃
We watched over Adam and Eve.
看见他们的弱点和爱
Saw their frailty and their love.
也目睹他们堕落，并怜悯他们
And then we saw their fall.  And we pitied them.
那时我们不是石头，而是光芒
We were not stone then, but light.
我们没有资格插手
It was not our place to interfere.
却选择尽力帮助人类
Yet we chose to try and help mankind.
因此违背了造物主的旨意
And when we disobeyed The Creator,
所以他惩罚我们
He punished us.
让我们被你们的世界包覆
We were encrusted by your world.
火焰般的光芒被岩石和泥巴遮盖
Rock and mud shackled our fiery glow.
但我们仍将所有知识传授给人
Still, we taught mankind  all we knew of Creation.
在我们的帮助下
With our help,
人从尘土中崛起  变得伟大且不可一世
they rose from the dust,  became great and mighty.
然后把我们的恩惠转为暴行
But then  they turned our gifts to violence.
只有一人保护我们
Only one man protected us.
你的祖父玛土撒拉
Your grandfather Methuselah.
我们几乎被赶尽杀绝
We were hunted. Most of us killed.
活下来的则继续困在石壳里
Those who lived were left prisoners  in these stony shells,
被放逐在这片贫瘠的大地上
marooned upon this barren land.
我们恳求造物主带我们回家
We begged The Creator  to take us home.
但他总是沉默
But He was always silent.
现在…
And now
你却说你听见了他的呼唤
you claim that  you have heard His call.
撒米亚扎无法接受
Samyaza cannot accept this.
就凭你一个人？  人可是破坏世界的元凶
A man?  When it is men who broke the world.
但当我看着你
But I look at you
就好像又看见了亚当
and I see a glimmer of Adam again.
我所认识的人
The man I knew.
我前来帮助的人
The man I came to help.
我为什么不能去？
Why can't I come?
因为我要你照顾妈妈
Because I need you to look after Mother.
懂吗？
Do you understand?
好好照顾爸爸
And you look after your father.
看顾他们
Watch over them.
你大可以放心
They are in good hands.
祖父？
Grandfather?
诺亚
Noah.
这是你的曾祖父，要尊敬他
This is your great-grandfather.  Show him respect.
告诉他你的名字
Tell him your name.
我叫闪
I am Shem.
我的长子
My eldest.
靠近一点
Come closer.
让我看看你
Let me see you.
你是个幸运的孩子
You're a lucky boy.
你一定长得像妈妈，不像爸爸
I think  you must have your mother's looks,  not your father's.
过来让曾祖父认识你
Come tell me about yourself.
我问你
So,
世界上你最喜欢什么？
what do you like most in the world?
- 莓果  - 你说什么？
Berries.  What?
莓果，莓果，当然了
Berries.  Berries, yes.
没有什么比鲜甜的莓果更好吃了
What can compete with  fresh, ripe berries? Nothing.
太久没吃我都快忘了它们的滋味
Yes, it's been so long I can barely  remember the taste of them.
你有没有带一些来给我吃？
Tell me, did you bring me any?
没有吗？
No?
我现在好想吃
I'm craving them now.
好吧，可能以后还有机会
Well, perhaps one day.
爬这么长一段路，你一定累了
You must be tired.  It's a long way up here.  Yeah.
休息一下吧？
Why not rest?
这样就行了
How perfect.
我们要讨论的话题不适合孩子
What we need to discuss  is not for boys.
- 你知道我来的原因？  - 是的
You know why I've come?  Yes.
我父亲以诺临终前曾告诉我
Before he walked on,  my father Enoch told me that one day,
人若不知悔改
if man continued in his ways,
造物主将摧毁这个世界
The Creator would annihilate this world.
所以我看到的即将成真？
So what I saw is true?
所有生命都将因人的恶行而抹杀？
All life blotted out  because of what man has done?
还有挽救的余地吗？
Can it not be averted?
他一定会用你能了解的方法让你知道
Noah, you must trust that He speaks  in a way that you can understand.
告诉我，这场灾难是否能够避免？
So you tell me.  Can this destruction be averted?
不能
No.
但他要我来这里
He sent me here.
如果我阻挡不了，为什么还要我来？
Why send me  if there's nothing I can do to stop it?
他可能只是要你来…
Well, perhaps He simply sends you here
…跟我这老头喝杯茶
to share a cup of tea with an old man.
你还看见了什么？
So, is that all you saw?
除了这里以及毁灭世界的烈焰？
The fires of destruction on this place?
不，不是火
No, not fire.
- 是水  - 水？
- Water.  - Water?
我父亲说会是火
My father said it would be fire.
我看见了水，水带来死亡
I saw water. Death by water.
我看见了死亡
I saw death.
也看见了新生命
And I saw new life.
还有别的，祖父
There's something more, Grandfather.
一件我该做的事
Something I'm to do.
我知道的
I know it.
但我之前没看出来
I just didn't see what it was.
新的生命
New life.
或许你还有东西没看见
Well, perhaps  there is more for you to see.
他难道不是要你来跟老头喝杯茶吗？
Did He not send you here to  drink a cup of tea with an old man?
药就是难吃
The medicine always tastes bad.
- 她是唯一活着的人  - 她伤得很重吗？
She was the only one moving.  Was she hurt badly?
她的肚皮上有个很大的伤口
She had a big cut on her belly.
妈妈帮她，我则握住她的手
Mother helped and I held her hand.
她一定觉得很安心
That must have made her feel safe.
怎么样？
Well?
火会吞噬一切
Fire consumes all.
水能洗清罪恶
Water cleanses.
将肮脏与纯洁隔离  邪恶与无辜分开
It separates the foul from the pure.  The wicked from the innocent.
恶则向下沉沦  善则向上提升
And that which sinks  from that which rises.
他要摧毁一切…
He destroys all,
…是为了重新来过
but only to start again.
你确定？
You sure?
确定
Yes.
风暴无法避免
The storm cannot be stopped.
但可以求存
But it can be survived.
你可能会需要这个
You may need this.
这是一颗种子
It's a seed.
它来自最早的花园
From the first Garden.
伊甸园
From Eden.
记住，诺亚
Remember, Noah,
他选择你是有原因的
He chose you for a reason.
你抓不到我！
You can't get me!
爸爸！
Dada!
我的祖父还活着
My grandfather lives.
他让我看清楚我们来这里的目的
He's helped me see  what we're here to do.
人将因其所作所为而受罚
Men are going to be punished  for what they've done to this world.
毁灭即将来临
There will be destruction.
悲剧就要发生
There will be tragedy.
我们家族被赋予重任
And our family  has been chosen for a great task.
我们被选来解救无辜的生命
We've been chosen  to save the innocent.
无辜的生命？
The innocent?
动物
The animals.
它们为什么是无辜的？
Why are they innocent?
因为它们仍依照伊甸园的方式过活
Because they still live  as they did in the Garden.
没错
Yes.
我们必须拯救足够的动物
And we need to save enough of them
让生命重新开始
to start again.
那我们怎么办？
But what of us?
我们也会重新来过
I guess we get to start again, too.
在更美好的新世界里重新来过
We get to start again  in a new and better world.
不过在那之前
But first
- 必须先建造  - 建造什么？
we have to build.  Build What?
大洪水要来了
A great flood is coming.
天上的水和地上的水将汇合
The waters of the heavens  will meet the waters of the earth.
我们要造船来度过风暴
We build a vessel to survive the storm.
我们要建造一艘方舟
We build an ark.
把叛徒带回去
Take the traitor back.
他是长者的子嗣！
He is a child of the old one!
别走！
Stop!
我们被赋予任务，帮助我们
There is work to do. Help us.
帮助你们？
Help you?
我们曾经帮助过人
We tried to help your kind once.
但你们害我们失去一切！
And we lost everything because of you!
还不是一切
Not everything.
我们可以拯救其余生命，再次服侍他
We can save what is left.  We can serve Him again.
你们都是背信忘义的蛇！
You treacherous snake!
造物主
The Creator.
孩子们！
Children!
这是什么？
What is this?
这是…
This...
这是我们的方舟
This is our ark.
我们将帮助这个人
We will help this man.
不
No!
闪
Shem.
别这样
Wait.
拜托
Please.
还会痛吗？
It still hurts?
含！
Ham!
闪！
Shem!
他没有人陪
He doesn't have anyone.
我们走
Come.
爸爸，你看见了吗？
Father, did you see them?
爸爸？
Father?
看见了，雅弗
Yes, Japheth.
风暴要来了
It begins.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
它睡着了
It sleeps.
动作轻一点
Gently.
你瞧，一只公的和一只母的
See, that's a boy one  and that's a girl one.
风暴过后，它们会成为父母
After the storm,  they'll become a mother and a father.
孵出来的雏鸟将在大地上生生不息
And the hatchlings will spread  right across the world.
我们必须温柔对待它们
We have to be gentle with them
好好保护它们
and we have to be protective.
万一它们有了什么闪失
If something were to happen,
创世的一小部分就会永远消失
that would be  a small piece of Creation lost forever.
这些无辜的动物现在交付我们手中
All of these innocent creatures  are now in our care.
我们的工作就是照顾它们
It's our job to look after them.
爸爸？
Father?
所有鸟都成双成对
All the birds are two.
你有妈妈，闪有伊拉
You have Mother, Shem has Ila.
那我呢？
But what of me?
雅弗呢？
What of Japheth?
谁会是我们的另一半？
Who is there for us?
你看见他造林让我们有木材建方舟
Did you see how He made the forest  to give us wood for the ark?
也看见他把鸟送过来
How He sent the birds?
你想想…
So,
他不是给了我们所需的东西吗？
hasn't He sent everything we need?
妈妈！
Mother!
怎么了？
What is it? What?
蛇来了！
Snakes!
- 蛇也会来？  - 是的
- Snakes are coming, too?  - Yeah.
所有在地上爬行蠕动的都会来
All that creeps, all that crawls,  all that slithers.
没事的
It's all right.
爸爸！爸爸！
Father! Father!
别怕
Don't be afraid.
谁都不准伤害这个男孩
No one will hurt this boy.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
- 含  - 含？
- Ham.  - Ham?
我是土拔尔 - 该隐
I am Tubal-Cain.
你认识我吗？
Do you know me?
你不认识你的王？
You don't know your king?
我父亲说造物主的花园里不能有王
My father says there can be no king  in The Creator's garden.
含，过来
Ham, come here.
别带走我最优秀的士兵
Do not take my best soldier.
他不属于你们
He's nothing of yours.
看看他拿武器的样子
Look at his hand on that weapon.
我相信他是我们的一分子
I believe he is something of mine.
含
Ham.
东西放下
Leave it.
- 不，他给了我  - 听话
- No, he gave it to me.  - Do what I tell you.
有人说奇迹发生  我斥为无稽之谈
When I heard talk of miracles,  I dismissed them.
但我亲眼看见鸟群飞来
But then I saw the birds  with my own eyes, flying here,
因此想一探究竟
and I had to come.
- 这里没有东西可以给你  - 是吗？
There isn't anything for you here.  No?
所有东西都是我的
This all belongs to me.
这块土地，这片森林
This land. This forest.
还有你盖的那座堡垒
That stronghold of yours.
你真的以为躲在那里就能逃离我？
Did you really think you could  protect yourself from me in that?
那不是为了逃离你而盖的
It's not protection from you.
不然是为了什么？
Then what is it?
这艘方舟…
An ark
…会在造物主以洪水清除世上罪恶时…
to hold the innocent
…保护无辜性命
when The Creator sends his deluge  to wipe out the wicked from this world.
造物主才不在乎这世界变成怎么样
The Creator does not care  what happens in this world.
他标记该隐后便无声无息
Nobody has heard from Him  since He marked Cain.
我们无依无靠  是被抛弃的孩子
We are alone.  Orphaned children,
受到诅咒
cursed to struggle by
必须汗流浃背才得以苟且偷生
the sweat of our brow to survive.
所以我不择手段也要活下去
Damned if I don't do everything  it takes to do just that.
所以我要什么就去拿
Damned if I don't take what I want.
我们见过面吗？
We have met?
我是拉麦的儿子！
I am the son of Lamech!
塞特的第八代子孙！
Eight generations descended from Seth!
回到该隐为你们建立的城市去
Return to your cities of Cain!
我们都已经受到审判！
Know we have all been judged!
我拥有千万大军
I have men at my back,
凭你一个人就想抵抗我？
and you stand alone and defy me?
我并非独自一人
I'm not alone.
Take the children!
别害怕，我的子民！
Do not fear, my people!
别害怕！站稳脚步！
Don't be afraid! Stand!  Hold your line, men.
他的奴才跟你站在同一阵线？
His minions, they're with you?
奇迹？你说洪水会来？
Miracles? A deluge, you claim?
或许你是对的
Well, perhaps you're right.
或许把我们逐出伊甸园还不够
Perhaps casting us out of Paradise  was not enough.
他要回来把我们解决掉
Perhaps, He returns to finish us off.
如果是这样…
Well, if He does,
…我会乘上你那艘船度过风暴
I will ride the storm in that ship of yours.
你和你的子民都无处可逃
There is no escape  for you and your kind.
你的大限已到
Your time is done.
- 大地正在死去  - 含
- The land is dying.  - Ham.
- 城市已经凋零  - 别再听他说了
- The cities are dead.  - Don't listen to him.
我的子民追随我！
My people follow me!
更多人会追随他们！
And more will follow them!
我才不怕奇迹  拉麦之子！
I'm not afraid of miracles,  son of Lamech!
你现在拒绝我们少数人
If you refuse my dozens now,
那就等着我带多数人回来！
I shall return with legions!
走
Move.
爸爸？
Father?
他们真的会带更多人来吗？
Will so many really come?
我们必须尽快建好方舟
We need to finish as fast as we can.
大雨下得愈早愈好
The sooner He sends the rain,  the better.
到时我们在里面就安全了
Until then, we're safer inside.
我们全面动员
We build.
先是武器，再来是人
First weapons, then men.
只有能战斗的人可以吃饭
Feed only those that will fight.
给他们装备
Arm them, train them,
训练他们，让他们无所不能
and there is nothing they can't do.
只要军队够强大，就可以击溃那些巨人
With an army,  we can crush those giants.
我们快饿死了！给我们肉！求求你！
Please, we're hungry!  - Give us meat.  - Our children are starving.  Please help us!
放我们走！
Let us go!
我们要饿死了！
We're starving!
我等一下再过来好了
Should I come back?
没事的
No.
那些人会来攻击我们吗？
Do you think  those men are going to attack us?
大雨来的时候就会
When the rain comes.
那会是什么情景？
What do you think it'll be like?
我在脑海中见过了
I've imagined it.
万物死亡的惨状
Seeing that much death,
难以言喻
I'm not sure there are words.
所有生命都将结束
The end of everything.
但也将重生
The beginning.
一切都将重头来过
The beginning of everything.
怎么了？
So what is it?
不管闪说了或做了什么
Whatever he's done or said,
他都是喜欢你的
Shem is very fond of you.
闪需要一个女人
Shem needs a woman.
真正的女人
A real woman.
他应该建立自己的家庭
He should have a family.
但我却无法给他
I can't give any of that to him.
即使他愿意
And I'm not going to  deny him those things,
我也不会要他这么牺牲
even if he wants me to.
我不会这么做
I won't do it.
再说…
Besides,
…造物主才不会让一个不孕的女孩…
why would The Creator
…待在他的方舟上
want a barren girl on His ark?
伊拉，伊拉
Ila. Ila.
我们一开始收容你的时候
When we first took you in,
我认为你会是个负担
I thought you were going to be a burden.
而且我不想再看见被这世界腐化的…
And I didn't want to see
…任何一个人
anybody else ruined by this world.
但我错了
But I was wrong.
你是上天赋予的礼物
You're a gift.
珍贵不已的礼物
A precious, precious gift.
千万别忘记这一点
Just don't forget  how precious a gift you are.
我知道你会帮含和雅弗找到妻子
I know you'll be going to find wives  for Ham and Japheth.
你也应该帮闪找一个
- You should find one for Shem, too.  - Ila.
你想逃到哪里？
Where do you think you're going?
别带走我的宝贝女儿！
Please, please don't take my baby!
放开她们！求求你！
Let them go! Please!
对不起，我们得填饱肚子！
Sorry, we have to eat!
我的宝贝女儿！住手！
Don't take my baby! No!
别带走我的宝贝！快阻止他！
Don't take my baby!  No, no, please will you stop him?
放开她们！
Let them go!
不
No!
别挣扎了 !
Quit struggling! It'll be easier.
跟我走！少白费力气！
Come with me! Stop struggling!
你！是你！
You! You!
我这里有两个女孩和你们交易！
I have two girls! I have two girls to trade!
女孩给你们！肉给我！快！
Take the girls! Give me the meat!  Give it to me!
怎么了？
What happened?
这些东西全都早该放进去了
All of this should be inside by now.
- 风暴要来了  - 我们的妻子在哪？
The storm is coming.  What about our wives? Where are they?
- 你没听见我的话吗？  - 她们何时来？
Did you not hear what I just said?  But when are they coming?
不会有什么妻子
There will be no wives.
什么？不行！
What? What? No!
你说过造物主会给我们所需的东西
You said that The Creator  would give us what we'll need.
去帮你哥哥
- Help your brother.  - No.
不！你不能这样！
Listen. Listen, you can't do this!
我要怎么当个男人？
You can't.  How am I supposed to be a man?
我要你去帮你哥哥
I said help your brother.
- 你要我永远长不大！  - 不是的！
You want me to stay a child!  No!
我现在要求你当个男人
I'm asking you to be a man
做你该做的事
and do what needs to be done.
含！
Ham!
你这是做什么，诺亚？
What are you doing, Noah?
邪恶的不只其他人
The wickedness is not just in them.
我们所有人都一样
It's in all of us.
我见识过了
I saw it.
不
No.
诺亚
Noah.
我们是善良的
There's goodness in us.
看看我们的孩子
Look at our boys.
闪忠心耿耿，雅弗宅心仁厚
Shem's loyalty. Japheth's kindness.
含正直诚实
Ham's integrity.
他们都是好人
Good men.
也会成为好父亲
They'd be good fathers.
闪被欲望所蒙蔽
Shem is blinded by desire.
含贪求身外之物
Ham is covetous.
雅弗只会讨好他人
And Japheth lives only to please.
我也没好到哪里去
I am no better.
至于你
And you?
只要是为了那三个孩子
Is there anything you would not do,
不管好事坏事都做得出来
good or bad, for those three boys?
只要是为了保护孩子…
We would both choose to kill
- 我们杀人放火也愿意  - 是的
in order to protect our children. Yes.
我们与他人并无不同
We're no different.
既自私又懦弱
We were weak and we were selfish
还以为能和邪恶划清界线
to think we could set ourselves apart.
我们要努力…
We will work,
完成任务…
complete the task,
然后死去
and then we'll die.
就和世人一样
The same as everyone else.
他们都还是孩子！
They are children!
我们的孩子，诺亚！
They are our children, Noah!
你一点慈悲心都没有吗？
Have you no mercy?
慈悲的时间已过
The time for mercy has passed.
天罚就要降临
Now our punishment begins.
含！
Ham!
祖父？
Grandfather?
你带了东西来给我吗？
Did you bring me something?
诺亚种了我给他的种子吗？
Did Noah plant the seed I gave him?
是的
Yes.
那么大的森林里没有莓果吗？
And in all that forest  there were no berries?
闪说要带莓果来给我吃的
Shem promised me berries.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不知道这件事
I didn't know.
太可惜了
It's a pity.
那你为什么来这里？
Then why did you come here?
因为诺亚
It's Noah.
他不让我们的儿子传宗接代
He leaves our boys with no one.
闪有伊拉，但她不能生育
Shem has Ila, but she's barren.
我们家不会有其他妻子
There'll be no other wives,
也就不会有下一代
so no children.
这是正义
Justice.
造物主必须摧毁被人破坏殆尽的世界
The Creator destroys this world  because we corrupted it.
因此我们也应该被消灭
So we ourselves must be destroyed.
不
No.
我不相信
I can't believe that's true.
我的儿子们不该有这种下场
Not when I look at my sons.
他们渴望的只有爱
All they desire is love.
难道这样还不够让他们成为好人吗？
Isn't that all their hearts need  to be good?
谁是好人？谁又是坏人？
Who is good? Who is wicked?
我怎么知道是非对错？
How am I supposed to know  what is right?
选择在诺亚手中  你我都无权决定
That choice is Noah's.  Not mine. Not yours.
他看来已经下定决心
It sounds like he has made it.
这么说您是不会帮我了
So then you will not help me?
我不知道我帮不帮得了你
I don't know if I even could.
就算可以，帮助你可能会带来痛苦
But if I tried, it could cause pain
甚至悲剧
and possibly tragedy.
到头来选择还是会落在诺亚手中
And in the end,  it would just come back to Noah again.
这是你要的吗？
Is that what you wish?
我要我的孩子们生儿育女
I want my sons to have children.
我要他们快乐
I want them to be happy.
我无法想像他们孤独老死
I can't bear to think of them dying alone.
让开！我们要过去！
Out of the way! Coming through!
拜托！
Please!
走开！
Get away!
不…
No. No, no...
没事的，我不会伤害你
It's all right. It's all right. I'm not...  I'm not going to hurt you.
我有吃的
I have food.
拿去
Here.
你想怎么样？
What do you want?
没怎样
Nothing.
你自己一个人吗？
Are you alone?
是啊
Yes.
你呢？
And you?
我可以带你逃出去
I can help you get away.
不要
No.
好吧，那我就多待一会儿
Well, then, I'll stay a little while.
可以吗？
If that is all right?
我叫…
My name
…娜儿
is Na'el.
闪！
Shem!
把大家找回来
Go and find them and bring them back.
小心点
Be careful.
含？
Ham?
别怕，小孙女
Don't be afraid, granddaughter.
别怕
Don't be afraid.
- 您是祖父？  - 是的
Grandfather?  Yes.
您在这里做什么？
What are you doing down here?
我在找我想吃的莓果
I'm looking for berries. I have a craving.
帮我找找，我的视力已经不如以往
Come and help me look for them.  My eyes aren't  as good as they used to be.
- 我得去找含  - 时间还很够
I have to find Ham.  There's time enough for that.
过来
Come here.
Come.
来这里帮我
Come here and help me.
就在这附近
They're here somewhere.
这附近有莓果
They're here somewhere, berries.
我知道就在这里
I know there are berries.
这里什么也没有，祖父
There's nothing here, Grandfather.
- 我带您去找诺亚  - 不
- Let me take you to Noah.  - No.
没必要，你可以走了
No need for that. You go now.
去吧
You go.
等等，等等
Wait. Wait.
这十年来你和我的家族一起生活
Ten years you've been with my own.  With my own family.
十年了，你爱他们吗？
Ten years. And you love them?
闪？还有诺亚？
Shem? And Noah?
诺亚救了我一命
He saved my life.
- 抚养我长大  - 是的
Raised me.  Yes, he did.
的确如此
Yes.
你就像他的亲生女儿
And you are now as his own daughter.
就像我的曾孙女
My own great-granddaughter.
这十年来你受我家族庇护
Ten years in the shadow of my home,
我却没能赐福给你
and yet  I have never given you my blessing.
让我弥补你
May I?
含！伊拉！
Ham! Ila!
你可以走了，去找他吧
You can go now. Go to him.
去吧，快
You go. Go now.
伊拉！
Ila!
我们必须回…
We have to get back...
我们必须离开
We have to go.
我们必须离开，走吧，快！
We have to go. Come on. Now!
我是人
I am a man.
你以你的形像造我
Made in Your image.
为什么你不与我交谈？
Why will You not converse with me?
我赋予生命
I give life.
也可以夺走生命，就跟你一样
I take life away. As You do!
我跟你很像，不是吗？
And I am like You, am I not?
跟我说话
Speak to me.
跟我说话！
Speak to me!
风暴来了！
It has begun!
上天要置我们于死地！
Death comes from the heavens!
这场大雨…
This rain
…想让我们从世界上消失
is meant to wash us off  the face of this world.
但我们是人
But we are men.
生死操之在己
We decide if we live or die.
我们是人！
We are men!
只要团结起来便所向披靡！
And men united are invincible!
你们想活下去吗？
Do you want to live?
Yeah!
那就把巨人杀了！
We kill the giants!
把诺亚杀了！
We kill Noah!
夺下方舟！
We take the ark!
Yeah!
诺亚！
Noah!
含呢？
Where's Ham?
救我出去，快！
Get it off me, no!
不！不
No,no,no!
不逃不行！
We have to get away!
我不会离开你，我不会！
I won't leave you. I won't!
含！
Ham!
爸爸，帮帮我们！
Father, help! Help!
- 救救她！  - 救我出去！
- Help her!  - Help me, please!
拜托，救我！
Please, help me, please!
救命啊！
Please... Someone please help me!
救我！
Help me!
不要！
No!
含！含！
Ham! Ham!  Ham!
含！
Ham!
撒米亚扎！
Samyaza!
撒米亚扎！  撒米亚扎！
Samyaza! Samyaza!
- 诺亚！  - 含呢？
- Noah!  - Where is Ham?
他过去了！  动作快！
Ham is through! Quickly!
快跑！
Run!
含
Ham.
含！
Ham!
加快速度！
Faster!
前进！
Forward!
保护妈妈和家人
Protect your mother. Protect them all.
散开！
Part!
造物主…
My Creator,
…原谅我
forgive me.
造物主带他回家了
The Creator brings him home.
含？
Ham?
闪，进去
Shem. Shem, go inside.
快进去
Go inside.
他们正在逼近，快进去！
They are upon us. Go inside!
再见了，亚当之子
Good-bye, son of Adam.
儿子，你在哪里？
Son, where are you?
含！
Ham!
含？
Ham?
没事的
It's all right.
- 闪！  - 爸爸！
- Shem!  - Father!
- 雅弗，你在哪？  - 伊拉，我在这！
Japheth, where are you?  - Ila, I'm here!  - Father!
妈妈，爸爸在哪？
Mother, where's Father?
求求你，诺亚
Please, Noah,
一定有方法可以救他们
there must be something we can do.
我们可以抛下绳索
We can drag ropes.
那些人并非全是士兵，爸爸
They cannot all be soldiers, Father.
他们只是凡人，方舟还有空间
They are just people. And there's room.
这里没有容纳他们的空间
There is no room for them.
我们所知的世界很快就要消失
Soon everything we knew will be gone.
创世遗留下来的生命都在这艘船上了
All that is left of Creation  will lie within these walls.
外面…
Outside,
…只是回到纷乱混沌的状态而已
just the waters of chaos again.
你们很愤怒
You are angry.
你们批判我
You judge me.
我讲一个故事给你们听
Let me tell you a story.
这是我父亲告诉我的第一个故事
The first story my father told me,
也是我告诉你们的第一个故事
and the first story that I told each of you.
一开始…
In the beginning,
…什么也没有
there was nothing.
只有无尽无声的黑暗
Nothing but the silence  of an infinite darkness.
造物主的气息拂过虚空的表面
But the breath of The Creator  fluttered against
轻声说…
the face of the void, whispering,
…“要有光”
"Let there be light. "
就有了光
And light was.
光是好的
And it was good.
这是第一天
The first day.
无形的光开始组成物质并有了形状
And then the formless light  began to take on substance and shape.
这是第二天
A second day.
接着我们的世界诞生了
And our world was born.
一个美丽又脆弱的家园
Our beautiful, fragile home.
一道强大温暖的光滋养了白昼
And a great,  warming light nurtured its days.
一道较小的光统治着黑夜
And a lesser light ruled the nights.
也开始有夜晚与早晨
And there was evening. And morning.
新的一天
Another day.
世上的水聚在一处
And the waters of the world  gathered together,
使旱地露出来
and in their midst emerged dry land.
这样又过了一天
Another day passed.
地上长出生物
And the ground put forth  the growing things.
厚厚一层植物遍布大地
A thick blanket of green  stretching across all Creation.
水中也生意盎然
And the waters, too, teemed with life.
充斥今日不复存在的奇妙生物
Great creatures of the deep  that are no more.
鱼种众多，有些可能仍在深海中游动
Vast multitudes of fish,  some of which may still  swim beneath these seas.
不久天上已满是飞鸟
And soon  the sky was streaming with birds.
黑夜过去，白昼降临，这是第五天
And there was evening.  And there was morning. A fifth day.
现在全世界都充满着生命
Now the whole world  was full of living beings.
大地上有各式各样的野兽与爬虫
Everything that creeps,  everything that crawls,  and every beast  that walks upon the ground.
这是好的，全都是好的
And it was good. It was all good.
光，空气，水合泥土皆洁净不受污染
There was light and air and water  and soil, all clean and unspoiled.
植物和虫鱼鸟兽生活其中
There were plants and fish  and fowl and beast,
各从其类，各安其分，各得其所
each after their own kind.  All part of the greater whole.  All in their place.
万物平衡，这是乐园
And all was in balance. It was paradise.
是造物主掌上的宝石
A jewel in The Creator's palm.
接着造物主创造了男人
Then The Creator made Man.
并创造了女人
And by his side, Woman.
他们就是所有人类的父母
Father and mother of us all.
他给他们一个选择
He gave them a choice.
是顺从黑暗的诱惑
Follow the temptation of darkness
还是把握光明的祝福
or hold on to the blessing of light.
但他们吃了禁果
But they ate from the forbidden fruit.
从此失去了纯真
Their innocence was extinguished.
亚当的子孙到了第十代，罪恶…
And so for the ten generations since Adam,
…一直存在我们内心
sin has walked within us.
兄弟反目成仇
Brother against brother.
国家兵戎相向
Nation against nation.
人类迫害万物
Man against Creation.
我们自相残杀
We murdered each other.
世界被破坏殆尽，这是我们造成的
We broke the world. We did this.
是人造成的
Man did this.
世上所有的美好…
Everything that was beautiful,
…与良善…
everything that was good,
…皆被人摧毁
we shattered.
现在…
Now,
…一切重新开始
it begins again.
水，空气，泥土，植物和虫鱼鸟兽
Air, water, earth, plant,  fish, bird and beast.
乐园将再现
Paradise returns.
但这一次…
But this time,
…没有人的容身之地
this time there will be no men.
如果人再进入伊甸园
If we were to enter the Garden again,
伊甸园就只会再度被摧毁
it would only be to destroy it once more.
不
No.
造物主已经做出审判
The Creator has judged us.
人类必须灭绝
Mankind must end.
闪和伊拉…
Shem and Ila,
…你们将埋葬我和妈妈
you will bury your mother and I.
含，你将埋葬他们
Ham, you will bury them.
雅弗将为你送终
Japheth will lay you to rest.
而你，雅弗…
You, Japheth,
…你会是最后一名人类
you will be the last man.
终究也会归于尘土
And in time you, too,  will return to the dust.
世间万物会被留下
Creation will be left alone,
安全无虞，美丽如昔
safe and beautiful.
那个女孩的事我很抱歉
I'm very sorry about that girl.
我也为你感到遗憾
And I'm sorry for you.
但我们承担的责任…
But we have been entrusted with a task
…比个人私欲重要得多
much greater than our own desires.
含
Ham.
诺亚…
Noah...
他知道我在这里吗？
Does he know I'm here?
- 他知道吗？  - 不知道
- Does he know I'm here?  - No, no, no. No.
你为什么要帮我？
Why are you helping me?
我遇见一个女孩
There was a girl.
我试着带她上船
I tried to bring her.
他却眼睁睁让她丧命
But he just let her die.
所以你想报仇
And now you want revenge.
不
No.
是的，你想
Yes, you do.
你想报仇
陆地完全消失了
There's no more land.
没有生物可以在外面存活
Everything out there must be dead.
这是他的旨意
It had to be what He wanted.
一个没有人的世界
A world without man.
你了解这一点吧？
You see that, don't you?
我只知道…
What I see
这件任务对你来说有多艰难
is how hard this was for you to do
因为你尊重生命
as a man who respects life,
也爱你的孩子
a man who loves his children.
你一直都很坚强
You've been strong.
你的工作完成了
But it's done.
已经大功告成
It's done now.
你可以卸下重担了
And you can put that burden down.
诺亚
Noah.
没事了
It's all right.
如果你父亲发现我  一定会杀了我
If your father found me,  he would kill me.
我们一定要做好准备  但我太虚弱了
We must be ready, but I am too weak.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我得恢复体力
I must get my strength back.
这些野兽很珍贵的  每种只有两只
The beasts are precious.  There are only two of each.
但我只有一个
And there is only one of me.
可是这场大雨和所有奇迹
But the rain, all these miracles,
都是为了要救它们
are for them.
救它们？
Them?
你父亲在船上载满野兽  却让孩童溺死
Your father fills a ship with beasts  while children drown.
他要你服侍动物根本贬低了你
He belittles you  by telling you you must serve them.
不是的
No.
是动物要服侍我们
They serve us.
这就是人的伟大之处
That is the greatness of men.
造物主创造了天地  海洋和这些野兽后
When The Creator  finished making the sky,  the ground, the sea, and this beast,
他并不满意
He wasn't satisfied.
他想创造出更伟大的东西  来支配统治万物
He needed something greater.  Something to take dominion over it  and subdue it.
因此他照着自己的形像创造人
So He made us in His image.
那就是我们
Us.
含，这世界属于你
This is your world, Ham.
你该掌握在手中
Seize it.
伊拉
Ila.
天啊，祖父
Grandfather.
怎么了？
What is it?
你没有生病
You're not sick.
但这不可能啊
But that's impossible.
怎么回事？
What? What is it?
诺亚
Noah.
这可是他的孙儿
It is his grandchild.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
- 爸爸  - 诺亚
- Father.  - Noah.
我们来请求你赐福
We've come to ask for your blessing.
我不懂你的意思
I don't understand.
我怀了孩子
I am with child.
不可能
It's not possible.
你没有生育能力
You're barren.
不可能怀孕
You can't conceive. How...
- 这怎么可能？  - 是祖父
- How is that possible?  - Grandfather.
- 我求祖父…  - 做什么？
I asked Grandfather...  To what?
破坏造物主的旨意？
Undermine The Creator?
求他给我们的孩子一个未来
To give our children a future.
给人类一个未来
To give humanity a future.
你知不知道你干了什么好事？
Have you any idea what you've done?
这么多的生命！这么多的人！
All those lives! All those people!
全死得毫无意义！
For nothing!
你知道接下来我被迫要做什么事吗？
Do you know what this forces me to do?
不！
No!
求求你！求求你！
Please! Please!
求求你！
Please!
我做不到！
I cannot do this!
请别让我这么做！
Tell me I don't need to do this!
求求你
Please.
你要我做的事，我哪一件没做到？
Have I not done  everything that You asked of me?
难道这样还不够吗？
Is that not enough?
你为什么不回答我？
Why do You not answer me?
为什么？
Why?
我不会让你失望
I will not fail You.
我必须这么做
It shall be done.
爸爸？
Father?
雨停了
The rains have stopped.
造物主对我们的孩子露出了笑容
The Creator smiles on our child.
雨的确是因为你们的孩子而停了
The rains have stopped  because of your child, yes,
但这不是笑容
but He does not smile.
如果你怀的是男孩
If your child is a boy,
他会代替雅弗成为最后一名人类
he will replace Japheth, last man.
如果是女孩
Ir it is a girl,
未来可能成为母亲
who could mature into a mother,
因此她必须死
she must die.
你疯了吗？
Are you mad?
这可是我的孩子！
That is my child!
如果你怀的是女孩
If you should bear a girl,
她一出生我就会亲手结束她的生命
in the moment of her birth,  I will cut her down.
妈妈！
Mother!
我的鸟回来了！
Mother, my bird!
什么也没有  连泥土都没沾上
Nothing. No mud.
毫无所获
Nothing.
我们还是得离开
We still have to go.
伊拉…
Ila,
…外面一片死寂
there's nothing.
什么也没有
There's nothing out there.
你们准备的食物和水  能撑多久？
You have food and water for how long?
几个星期？
Weeks?
- 一个月？  - 一个月
- A month?  - A month.
再等等吧
Please wait.
至少等鸟儿找到陆地  拜托
Wait until the bird finds land. Please.
雅弗，再让它去一趟
Japheth, send him again.
- 它太累了  - 送另一只去
- He's too tired.  - Then wake another.
给你
Here.
拜托了，让鸟儿帮我们找一个家
Please. One that can find us a home.
不
No.
我们今天就走
We leave today.
他们会死在外面
They will die out there.
留在船上就不会死
Not if they stay.
然后让你杀死他们的孩子？
And let you kill their child?
诺亚
Noah.
诺亚！
Noah!
是我害的
I did this.
是我害的，诺亚！
I did this, Noah!
我求你！
Please!
要罚就罚我！
Punish me!
我才该被惩罚，诺亚
Punish me, Noah!
不该是他们
Not them.
也不该是那个孩子
Not the child.
拜托你
Please.
不是只有那个孩子
The child is not being punished.
我们全都在受罚
We are all being punished.
无一例外
All of us.
我并不想这么做
It's not something I want to do.
但我必须这么做
It's something I have to do.
这么做很痛苦
It is painful,
但很公正
but it is just.
公正？
Just?
怎么会？
How?
这样怎么会是公正？
How is this just?
那是个婴儿啊，诺亚
It's a baby, Noah.
如果你一意孤行
If you hold to this,
你会失去你的儿子们，失去伊拉
you will lose your sons, you will lose Ila,
也会失去我
you will lose me.
我爱你，诺亚
I love you, Noah.
我追随你的脚步，与你同甘共苦
And I have followed you everywhere.  Through everything.
我原谅了你
I forgave you.
所有人都死了的时候，我原谅了你
When everyone was dead, I forgave you.
也准备和你相守至死
I was ready to die with you.
但这件事…
But this
…我永远都不会原谅你
I will never forgive.
不管是男婴女婴，我都不会原谅你！
Boy or girl, I will never forgive!
你会孤独地死去！
And you will die alone!
不仅孤独，还被怨恨！
Not just alone, but hated!
被每个你所爱的人怨恨！
Hated by everyone you love!
这才叫公正！
That is just!
That is just.
是时候了
It's time.
从那里引他过来
Bring him through there.
我会让他一招毙命
One blow will finish it.
你带着以防万一
Just in case, huh?
我不确定我做得到
I don't know if I can.
他杀了你的女人
He killed your woman.
现在还想杀了你哥哥的骨肉
And now  he plots to kill your brother's firstborn.
这是你要的结局吗？
Is that what you want?
你想让你姐姐死在海上吗？
You want your sister to die on the seas?
人并非由上天主宰
A man isn't ruled by the heavens.
而是由自己的意志主宰
A man is ruled by his will.
我问你
So I ask you,
你是不是人？
are you a man?
很好
Good.
因为如果你是人
Because if you're a man,
你就杀得下手
you can kill.
但他不会跟我来
But he won't follow me.
谢谢
Thank you, Japheth.
你要照顾好宝宝
You take care of that baby.
别害怕，妈妈
Don't be afraid, Mother.
我们会在新世界相聚
We'll see each other in the new world.
爸爸
Father.
住手！
No!
不可以！
你怎么能这么做？
How could you?
我以为你是善良的！
I thought you were good!
我以为这是他选择你的原因
I thought that's why He chose you.
他选择我是因为他知道我能完成任务
He chose me because  He knew I would complete the task,
仅此而已
nothing more, son.
妈妈
Mother.
你要生了
It's your time.
跟我来
Come. Come with me.
- 没事的  - 雅弗，留在原地
You're all right.  Japheth, stand back.
进来吧
Come now. Come inside.
就是这样
That's right. That's right.
你不会有事，伊拉  你在这里很安全
You're all right, Ila. You're safe here.
不要让宝宝出来
Please keep it inside.
孩子要出生了
Your baby's coming.
你的孩子要出生了  伊拉
Your baby's coming, Ila.
其他什么都别想
Don't think about anything else.
爸爸，动物醒来了
Father! Father, they're awake!
它们正在互相残食
They're awake!  They're eating each other!
- 那些野兽  - 你说什么？
- The beasts.  - What?
快来
Come.
快啊！
Come!
没有我们帮忙，它们不可能醒来
It's not possible for them  to have woken up without our help.
在哪里，儿子？
Which way, son?
这样就对了
That's right. That's right.
该隐的子孙
The line of Cain.
我告诉过你
I told you,
我才不怕奇迹
I'm not afraid of miracles.
就是这样
That's right.
这就对了
再用力点
A bit more.
是男孩还是女孩？
Boy or girl?
怎么回事？
What's happening?
还有一个
There's another.
有两个？
Two?
是双胞胎
Twins.
妈妈，怎么样？
Mother, so?
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
是一对姐妹
Sisters.
不
No.
不！
No!
我不会让他伤害我们的女儿
He will not touch our daughters.
不行！闪！
No! Shem!
闪！
Shem!
我杀死你父亲时早该连你一并解决
I should have killed you  when I killed your father.
现在就来做个了断
Well, now we finish it.
来吧！
Now!
新的伊甸园不容人类的邪恶存在
The evils of mankind  will not live in this new Eden.
离我们远一点！让我们自己过活！
Leave us! Leave us alone!
他由我来解决！
He's mine!
方舟，野兽和你们的女人…
The ark, the beasts,
…都由我来接收
and all of your women are now mine.
我会以我的形像…
I will build a new world
…建立一个新世界！
in my image!
现在…你是个人了
Now you are a man.
造物主还没有遗忘我们
The Creator has not forgotten us.
那个女孩叫娜儿
Her name was Na'el.
她是无辜的
She was innocent.
她是善良的
She was good.
是男孩
It's a boy.
- 是男孩  - 让开
- It's a boy.  - Move away.
是男孩
It's a boy.
伊拉在哪？
Where is she?
她在哪？
不行，不可以
No. No. No.
你不能这么做
You can't.
她们好漂亮
They're beautiful.
她们？
They?
你不能把两个孩子都杀了
You can't kill two.
他送来我们所需的东西
He sent us what we need.
不，不，不行！
No.No.No!
你不能这么做！
You can't!
不可以！
No!
诺亚
Noah!
伊拉
Ila!
诺亚
Noah.
求求你
Please.
她们是我的女儿！
These are my children!
- 你的孙女！  - 没人能阻止我
Your grandchildren!  I will not be stopped.
我知道我阻止不了你，但她们在哭
I know I cannot stop you,  but they're crying!
请别让她们哭着死去
Please don't let them die crying.
让我安抚她们
Let me calm them.
拜托，让她们能好好安息
Please, just let them be at peace.
月亮高挂
The moon is high
枝叶缠绕
The leaves entwine
你的父亲等待着…
Your Father waits for thee
…将你抱入怀中
To wrap you in His sheltering wings
轻声哄你入睡
To whisper you to sleep
将你抱入…
To wrap you in
…他的怀中
His welcoming arms
直到天空破晓
Till the night sky breaks
你的父亲是那疗愈的风
Your Father is the healing wind
轻声哄你入睡
That whispers you to sleep
轻声哄你们…
That whispers as
…入睡
You sleep
- 你不必在场  - 我要抱着她们
You do not need to see this.  I will hold them.
要杀就快
Do it quickly.
快动手呀！
Do it quickly!
我做不到
I cannot do this.
没事了
It's all right.
别睁开眼睛，雅弗
Hide your eyes, Japheth.
- 含呢？  - 他在这
- Ham?  - He's here.
你不必离开的
You don't have to go.
我不属于这里
I don't belong here.
不管怎么样…
For what it's worth,
我很高兴人类的香火由你延续下去
I'm glad that it begins again with you.
或许我们能变得善良
Maybe we'll learn to be kind.
他还会回来吗？
Will he come back?
有些伤害是无法弥补的
Some things cannot be unbroken.
我想知道…
I have to know...
…你为什么放过她们？
Why did you spare them?
当我低头看着那两个小女娃
I looked down at those two little girls,
我的心中只有爱
and all I had in my heart was love.
诺亚，那你为什么要独自过活？
Then why are you alone, Noah?
为什么远离你的家人？
Why are you separated  from your family?
因为我辜负了造物主
Because I failed Him.
也辜负了你们所有人
And I failed all of you.
是这样吗？
Did you?
诺亚，他选择你是有原因的
He chose you for a reason, Noah.
他让你看清人的邪恶
He showed you the wickedness of man
知道你不会视而不见
and knew you would not look away.
也让你看到人良善的一面
But then you saw goodness, too.
选择在你手中，因为这是他的旨意
The choice was put in your hands  because He put it there.
他让你决定我们是否值得救赎
He asked you to decide  if we were worth saving.
而你选择了…怜悯
And you chose mercy.
你选择了爱
You chose love.
他给了我们第二次机会
He has given us a second chance.
做一名父亲
Be a father.
做一名祖父
Be a grandfather.
请帮助我们变得更好
Help us to do better this time.
帮助我们重新开始
Help us start again.
造物主…
The Creator
…照着自己的形像创造亚当…
made Adam in His image,
…让他治理整个世界
and placed the world in his care.
这与生俱来的权力…
That birthright
…交给了我们
was passed down to us.
先是我的父亲，再给我…
To my father, then to me,
…然后是我的儿子们…
and to my sons,
闪
Shem,
雅弗
Japheth,
还有含
and Ham.
现在这项任务传承给你们…
That birthright is now passed to you,
…我们的孙女
our grandchildren.
这会是你们的工作
This will be your work,
也是你们的责任
and your responsibility.
我要你们…
So I say to you,
…滋生繁多…
be fruitful and multiply
…遍布大地
and replenish the earth.